Guide to the Franco Modigliani papers, 1936-2005 and undated, bulk 1970s-2003 RL.00905
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings and Speeches Series, 1936-2004 and undated, 58 boxes
  - Research and Writings Subseries, 1936-2004 and undated, bulk 1960-2003, 44 boxes
    - Mortgages
      - OPEN's IPM (Fund for an Open Society's inflation proof mortgage), 1985 (Box RW30)
      - Printed material, 1989-1994, 2 folders (Box RW30)
      - Spain, 1985 (Box RW30)
      - Variable rate mortgages
        - Contracts and correspondence, 1983-1984, 2 folders (Box RW30)
        - Correspondence, 1982-1991 and undated, 5 folders (Box RW31)
    - National savings regressions
      - 1990-1992 (Box RW31)
      - Rodriguez, Daniel, 1990 (Box RW31)
    - A New Look at the Monetary Mechanism, 1980-1981 (Box RW31)
    - New Mortgage Designs for Stable Housing in an Inflationary Economy..., with D. Lessard, 1976 (Box RW31)
    - Nineteen Economists Against the Martin Report - Correspondence, 1972 (Box RW31)
    - 1993: The Year of the Great Opportunity - Italian and English, 1993 (Box RW31)
    - No To Privatization..., undated (Box RW31)
    - Nota per i colleghi italiani su disoccupazione, inflazione..., with L. Buttiglione, 1993 (Box RW31)
    - Note on Definition of the Cost of Capital for Investment Under Inflation and Corporate Profit Taxes, undated (Box RW31)
    - Note on Macro-Economic Implication of the Costa Plan, 1976 (Box RW31)
    - Notes on the Foundation of the Red Sector, circa 1960 (Box RW31)
    - NSF Grant, Monetary Mechanism and Stabilization Policy Proposal (Box RW32)
      - Accounting statements, 1980-1984 (Box RW32)
      - Columbia University's subcontract, 1981-1984 (Box RW32)
      - Computer accounts, 1980-1984 (Box RW32)
      - Correspondence, 1979-1982 (Box RW32)
      - Drafts, 1979 Aug. (Box RW32)
      - Final report and notes, 1983-1984 (Box RW32)
      - Flow of funds project, 1972 (Box RW32)
      - MREH, undated (Box RW32)
      - Progress report, 1981 Oct. (Box RW32)
      - Students and secretaries, 1980-1983 (Box RW32)
    - 1944, 1963, and 1985, S. Fisher - Comment, F. Modigliani, 1986 (Martha's Vineyard conference) (Box RW32)
    - On the Role of Expectations of Price and Technological Change in an Investment Function, with A. Ando, R. Rasche, et al.
      - Correspondence and notes, circa 1973 (Box RW32)
      - Errata, 1972-1973 and undated (Box RW32)
    - On the Wealth of Nations, in Adam Smith's Legacy
      - Drafts and proofed corrections, 1990-1992 (Box RW32)
      - Drafts (early versions), circa 1990 (Box RW33)
      - Italian translation, 1991 (Box RW33)
    - Open letter about Patent Law S-507, 1997-1999, 2 folders (Box RW33)
    - Opportunities and Implications of a Return to Fixed Exchange Rates..., Yeager and Schwartz - Comment, F. Modigliani, 1982 (Box RW33)
    - Origin of the Depository Institutions Mess, J. Barthand and D. Brombaugh - Comment, F. Modigliani, circa 1991 (Box RW33)
    - Owens, Jim, 1995-1999 and undated, 2 folders (Box RW33)
    - Pasinetti debate - Correspondence and printed material, 1963-1985 (Box RW33)
    - Paul Samuelson and Modern Economics - Chapter by F. Modigliani, circa 1981 (Box RW33)
    - Paul Volcker: Changing Fortunes - Notes, circa 1992 (Box RW33)
    - Per Capita Income and the National Saving Rate..., 1992 (Box RW33)
    - Perotti, Enrico - Possible paper with F. Modigliani, 1990 (Box RW33)
    - Phillips curve, wage rigidity, Sargent model - Various unidentified notes, undated (Box RW33)
    - A Plan for Meeting the Domestic Food Shortage Without Price Control and Rationing, 1947 Dec., Folders 1-2 of 3 (Box RW33)
    - A Plan for Meeting the Domestic Food Shortage Without Price Control and Rationing, 1947 Dec., Folder 3 of 3 (Box RW34)
    - A Plan to Meet the Problem of Rising Meat and Other Food Prices Without Bureaucratic Controls, circa 1947 (Box RW34)
    - The Political Economy of Argentina, G. di Tell and R. Dornbusch - Comment, F. Modigliani, undated (Box RW34)
    - Principles of Corporate Finance, R. Brealey and S. Myers - Introduction, F. Modigliani, 1989-1990 (Box RW34)
    - Private Investment with Government Guarantees, undated (Box RW34)
    - Le privatizzazioni: chiarificazioni e suggerimenti
      - Correspondence, 1994 (Box RW34)
      - Drafts, 1994 (Box RW34)
    - A Proposal for Social Security, with M. Ceprini and A. Murahdlar - Publication letters, 2003 (Box RW34)
    - Proposition 3: Ballot question
      - Notes and correspondence, 1990 and undated (Box RW34)
      - Printed material, 1980-1990, 2 folders (Box RW34)
    - Publication permissions, 1994-2001 (Box RW34)
    - Rational expectations, business cycle, and monetary models
      - Papers, 1979-1981 and undated (Box RW34)
      - Printed material, 1982-1983 (Box RW34)
    - Readings in Monetary Theory - Notes, undated (Box RW34)
    - Reagan's Economic Policies, in Oxford Economic Papers, 1987-1988, Folder 1 of 3 (Box RW34)
    - Reagan's Economic Policies, in Oxford Economic Papers, 1987-1988, Folders 2-3 of 3 (Box RW35)
    - Recent Declines in the Savings Rate..., 1990 (Box RW35)
    - Reducing Unemployment in Europe..., with M. Moni, J.H. Drze, et al.
      - Correspondence and notes, 1986 (Box RW35)
      - Drafts, 1986 (Box RW35)
    - The Reform of the International Payment System, with H. Askari, 1971 (Box RW35)
    - Reform of the international payment system - SMR and Bhagwati, 1971-1973 (Box RW35)
    - La regolamentazione e la standardizzazione dei bilanci..., tesi di laurea, circa 1939 (Box RW35)
      Conditions Governing Access note
      Please handle with care.
    - The Relationship Between Cross-Sectional and Time Series Estimates of Parameters..., with J. Bossons, 1966 (Box RW35)
    - The Relationship Between Export and Import Prices..., with H. Askari, 1971-1973 (Box RW35)
    - The Relative Stability of Monetary Velocity and the Investment Multiplier, with A. Ando
      - Correspondence and data, 1964-1965, 2 folders (Box RW35)
    - [ The Relative Stability of Monetary Velocity and the Investment Multiplier?] - Lewis revisions, undated (Box RW36)
    - Reply to Professor A. Graziani, with R. Cohn, 1983 (Box RW36)
    - Resolving the Global Economic Crisis..., 1987, 2 folders (Box RW36)
    - Rethinking Pension Reform, with A. Muralidhar
      - Final version, 2003, 2 folders (Box RW36)
      - Latin American Pension Reforms..., 1998 (Box RW36)
      - Notes, 2003 (Box RW36)
    - Retirement Annuity Design in an Inflationary Climate, Z. Bodie and J. Pesando - Comments, F. Modigliani, 1984 (Box RW36)
    - Riforma del sistema previdenziale, with M. Ceprini, 2003 and undated (Box RW36)
    - The Rise in Corporate Leverage in the U.S., with J. Poterba, circa 1987 (Box RW36)
    - Risk Adjusted Performance (RAP): How to Measure It and Why, with L. Modigliani
      - Drafts and correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box RW36)
      - Printed material, 1996-2000, 2 folders (Box RW36)
      - Research notes, papers, and correspondence, 1996-1997, 2 folders (Box RW36)
    - The Role of Intergenerational Transfers and the Life-Cycle Saving in the Accumulation of Wealth (Box RW37)
      - Intergenerational Transfers and Saving, L. Kotlikoff, 1986 and undated (Box RW37)
      - The Contribution of Intergenerational Transfers to Total Wealth: A Reply, L. Kotlikoff and L. Summers, 1981-1986 (Box RW37)
      - Kotlikoff's papers, 1983-1984 (Box RW37)
      - Notes and correspondence, 1983-1986 (Box RW37)
      - Previous version, 1984-1986, 3 folders (Box RW37)
      - Reprints and correspondence, 1988-1991 (Box RW37)
    - The Role of Intergenerational Transfers in Aggregate Capital Accumulation, L. Kotlikoff and L. Summers - Comments, F. Modigliani, 1983 (Box RW37)
    - The Rules of the Game and the Development of Security Markets, with E. Perotti, 1989-1991 (Box RW37)
    - Saving and consumption behavior - Notes, 1974 (Box RW37)
    - Saving in Developing Countries: Growth, Income and Other Factors, 1990-1991, 2 folders (Box RW37)
    - Saving, Investment, and Growth, with M. Gibson, 1993-1995 (Box RW37)
    - Savings and inflation - Regressions, papers and notes, 1979-1982 and undated (Box RW38)
    - Savings, inflation and taxation
      - Papers, 1979-1981 (Box RW38)
      - Printed material, 1975-1980 (Box RW38)
    - Securities market - Martin report, 1971 (Box RW38)
    - The Shameful Rate of Unemployment in the EMS: Causes and Cures
      - Collignon version, 1995-1996 (Box RW38)
      - Correspondence and notes, 1994-1997 and undated (Box RW38)
      - Drafts, 1995-1997, 3 folders (Box RW38)
      - Draft and errata, 1996-2002; printed material, 1998 (Box RW38)
      - Frankfurt revision
        - Correspondence and notes, 1995 (Box RW38)
        - Printed material, 1995 (Box RW38)
    - Slides - E.F. Hutton Project, Cohn slides, Undated (Box RW39)
    - Small and medium businesses - Papers and note, 1990 and undated (Box RW39)
    - Social Science Quotations - Correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box RW39)
    - Social Security
      - Conference in Italy, 2000 (Box RW39)
      - Correspondence and research notes, 1996-2001, 3 folders (Box RW39)
      - Correspondence, research notes and regression tables, 2000-2001 (Box RW39)
      - Fondi Pensione, 1995-1996 (Box RW39)
      - How to Solve the Social Security Crisis, 2000-2001 and undated (Box RW39)
      - Information Project (SSIP), Washington Post, 2001 Oct. (Box RW39)
      - Italy
        - 1999-2000, 4 folders (Box RW39)
        - Newspaper discussions, 2002 (Box RW39)
      - MIT solution - A Better Solution to the Social Security Crisis: Funding with a Common Portfolio
        - Correspondence and research notes, 2001-2003; printed material, 2003 (Box RW39)
        - Data, circa 1999 (Box RW40)
        - Final draft, 2000-2002 (Box RW40)
      - Papers and printed material, 1988-2001 and undated, 7 folders (Box RW40)
      - Pension reform - Reports, data tables, and correspondence, 2000-2003 and undated (Box RW40)
      - Printed material, 2000 (Box RW40)
      - Private savings
        - Papers, 1979-1983 and undated, Folder 1 of 2 (Box RW40)
        - Papers, 1979-1983 and undated, Folder 2 of 2 (Box RW41)
        - Printed material, 1968-1979 (Box RW41)
        - Working Paper Series reports, 1979-1981 (Box RW41)
      - Reform, Steve Goss, comments on data, 2000 (Box RW41)
      - Reforming Pension Reform, with A. Muralidhar 1995-2002 (Box RW41)
      - Reforming Pension Reform, with A. Muralidhar--Referee Reports, 2001 (Box RW41)
      - Reply to Feldstein, 2001 Aug. 3 (Box RW41)
      - Workshop in Luxembourg, 2002 May 10-11 (Box RW41)
    - Some Economic Implications of the Indexing of Financial Assets..., 1974 (Box RW41)
    - Some Estimates of the Cost of Capital to the Electric Utility Industry, 1954-1957, with M. Miller, 1965 (Box RW41)
    - Some Proposals for Reform of the Discount Window, 1971 (Box RW41)
    - Some Reflections on Describing Structures..., with A. Ando, 1975 (Box RW41)
    - Sostenibilit e solvibilit del debito..., with F. Kostoris, 1997 (Box RW41)
    - Stock Market and Economy - Discussion notes, 1972 (Box RW41)
    - Studio Ambrosetti, 1981 (Box RW41)
    - The Supply of Money and the Control of Nominal Income, with L. Papademos, 1989-1990 (Box RW41)
    - Tarantelli, Enzio - Writings, research and correspondence, 1970-1988, Folders 1-2 of 3 (Box RW41)
    - Tarantelli, Enzio - Writings, research and correspondence, 1970-1988, Folder 3 of 3 (Box RW42)
    - Targets for Monetary Policy in the Coming Year, with L. Papademos, 1975 (Box RW42)
    - Taxation, Inflation, and Equity Values: Is There a Rational Linkage? R. Brinner and S. Brooks - Comments, F. Modigliani, 1979 Oct. (Box RW42)
    - Term structure
      - Correspondence and research notes, 1976-1978 and undated (Box RW42)
      - Printed material, 1966-1979 and undated (Box RW42)
    - A Theory and Test of Credit Rationing, with D. Jaffee, 1969-1976, 3 folders (Box RW42)
    - The Theory of Money and Interest in the Framework of General Equilibrium Analysis - Preliminary notes, undated, 2 folders (Box RW42)
    - Tivegna (Confindustria) - Comments on papers, 1983 (Box RW42)
    - Towards an Understanding of Real Effects and Costs of Inflation, with S. Fischer - Printed material, 1972-1976 and undated, Folders 1-2 of 3 (Box RW42)
    - Towards an Understanding of Real Effects and Costs of Inflation, with S. Fischer - Printed material, 1972-1976 and undated, Folder 3 of 3 (Box RW43)
    - Trade deficit - Correspondence, 2001 (Box RW43)
    - Traditional monetary mechanism - Notes and correspondence, 1979 and undated (Box RW43)
    - Twenty Five Years of Floating: Some Observations, with H. Askari, 1998 (Box RW43)
    - Unidentified research notes and loose notecards, undated, 2 folders (Box RW43)
    - Unidentified research notes and regressions, undated, 2 folders (Box RW43)
    - Unidentified research notes and transparencies, undated, 2 folders (Box RW43)
    - U.S. Deficits Since World War I, R. J. Barro - Comment, F. Modigliani, 1984-1986 (Box RW43)
    - Utility Analysis and Aggregate Consumption Functions: An Attempt at Integration, with R. Brumberg, 1953-1982 and undated, 4 folders (Box RW43)
    - The Valuation of Corporate Stock - Drafts and notes, 1971 (Box RW43)
    - Valuation of equity - Notes, undated (Box RW44)
    - Wealth-Income ratio - Basic data and sources, 1961 and undated, 2 folders (Box RW44)
    - Why Has the Italian National Saving Rate Declined? with T. Jappelli, 1989-1992 (Box RW44)
    - World Economic Outlook and Its Implications for Italy
      - Printed material, 1987-1988 (Box RW44)
      - Research notes, 1988 (Box RW44)
    - World Savings: An International Survey - Introduction, F. Modigliani
      - Correspondence, 1991-1993 (Box RW44)
      - Drafts, 1992 (Box RW44)
      - Research notes, 1991-1992 and undated, 3 folders (Box RW44)
  - Speeches and Lectures Subseries, 1966-2000, 7 boxes
    Consists of a selection of presentations and interviews given by Modigliani over the course of his career, focusing chiefly on the period from the 1970s up to the present. Many are in the Italian language. Includes a copy of the Nobel lecture, given in Stockholm in 1985, Life Cycle Individual Thrift and the Wealth of Nations. There is also a Spanish-language version. Some texts of lectures may also be found in the Articles Subseries of the Printed Materials Series; other interviews, many published in Italian newspapers and magazines, can be located in the Clippings Subseries of the Printed Materials Series. Lectures given as a teacher can be found in the Teaching Materials Series. Arranged in chronological order.
    - 1966 Oct., La situazione economica italiana e le sue prospettive (Box SL1)
    - 1967 Dec. 24, La sfida al dollaro (Box SL1)
    - 1968
      - Jan. 14, Il dollaro in castigo (Box SL1)
      - June 17-July 1, Rational Solutions of the International Liquidity Problem, Econometric Models of Stabilization Policy, 2 folders (Box SL1)
    - 1972 Jan. 22, Conversando con Modigliani (Box SL1)
    - 1973 Apr. 30, Speech on the life cycle hypothesis and the FMP model (Box SL1)
    - 1974
      - Aug. 9, Prospectives of World Trade: The Lessons of 1973-1974 (Box SL1)
      - Sept. 5, La ricetta Americana (Box SL1)
      - 1974-1997, Interviews - Notes, correspondence, and printed material (Box SL1)
    - 1975
      - Apr., Indexation (Box SL1)
      - May, Indexation in Theory and Practice (Box SL1)
      - Dec. 31, Diagnosi della crisi italiana e alternative di soluzione nel pensiero di Franco Modigliani (Box SL1)
      - The Meta Black Box (Box SL1)
    - 1976
      - Jan. 3, Nell'anno della ripresa economica gli italiani dovranno vivere peggio (Box SL1)
      - Feb. 1, Primo: la disoccupazione (Box SL1)
      - Feb. 4, Vi aspettano sudore e tasse (Box SL1)
      - Feb., Notes for Econometric Models Comparison Seminar (Box SL1)
      - Mar. 20, Chi pagherá per la crisi? (Box SL1)
      - Oct. 23, Modigliani: l'alto salario che provoca la disoccupazione (Box SL1)
      - Oct. 26, La situazione economica italiana (Box SL1)
      - Nov. 6-13, Repetita juvant? (Modigliani in Italia) (Box SL1)
      - Dec. 5, Andreotti non uscito dal ciclo infernale (Box SL1)
    - 1977
      - Mar. 16, Possiamo uscire dal ciclo infernale (Box SL1)
      - June 10, Attenti alle polveriere (Box SL1)
      - Oct. 3-7, Debate Over Stabilization Policy - Mattioli Lectures, Folder 1 of 5 (Box SL1)
      - Oct. 3-7, Debate Over Stabilization Policy - Mattioli Lectures, Folders 2-5 of 5 (Box SL2)
      - Oct. 9, Ma Modigliani ammonisce contro un rilancio prematuro (Box SL2)
      - Oct. 22, Quale sentiero di sviluppo? (Box SL2)
      - Nov., Monetary Mechanism and Its Relation to Financial Structure (Box SL2)
    - 1978
      - Jan. 21, Cari italiani, ecco i vostri mali, ecco qualche cura (interview) (Box SL2)
      - Feb. 2, Grido d'allarme di Modigliani (interview) (Box SL2)
      - Mar. 29, Non volere troppo (interview) (Box SL2)
      - Apr.
        - The Management of Exhaustible Resources and Future Generations (Box SL2)
        - Monetarism and the Choice of National Priorities (Box SL2)
      - Aug. 1, Operazione Europa: Quante cose da cambiare per prendere quel treno.... (interview) (Box SL2)
      - Oct. 11
        - Migliori di quanto pagano i conti delle imprese (interview) (Box SL2)
        - Un Modigiani ottimista sostiene che l'Italia giá fuori dalla crisi (interview) (Box SL2)
      - Oct., The Financial Goal of the Firm in a Market Economy (Box SL2)
    - 1979
      - Feb., Bergamo lecture (Box SL2)
      - Mar.
        - Tests of Stable Money Supply (Box SL2)
        - Theory of Exchange Rates (Box SL2)
      - May 10, The Stock Exchange (Box SL2)
      - Oct. 26-27, Inflation, Stock Market and Real Investments (Box SL2)
      - Anti-Inflation Policies (Box SL2)
      - Inflazione, indebitamento e valore azionario: conversazione con il Prof. Franco Modigliani (interview) - Informally published (Box SL2)
    - 1980
      - Jan., Professor Modigliani, ma l'inflazione che cos'è (interview) (Box SL2)
      - June, MIT/ILO symposium on financial markets (Box SL2)
      - Oct., MIT/ILO symposium on inflation (Box SL2)
    - 1981
      - Feb. 20, Monetary Policy of 1980 and the 80's (Box SL2)
      - Mar. 23, Stabilization Policy (Box SL2)
      - Aug. 13, The Accumulation of Individual and National Wealth and the Role of Social Security - Mattioli Lecture IV (Box SL2)
      - Oct., What's Wrong with Inflation (Box SL2)
      - Italian lectures (Box SL2)
    - 1983
      - Feb., Bentley College lecture (Box SL2)
      - Apr. 27-28, The Effects of Fiscal Policies: A Life Cycle Perspective - Marshall Lectures, Folder 1 of 6 (Box SL2)
      - Apr. 27-28, The Effects of Fiscal Policies: A Life Cycle Perspective - Marshall Lectures, Folders 2-6 of 6 (Box SL3)
      - IAP lectures (Box SL3)
    - 1984
      - May, Comment on Sjaastad (Box SL3)
      - June 3-4, Europe and the Dollar (Box SL3)
      - Dec. 6, Une rduction des impts est efficace lorsqu'elle apparat comme dfinitive (interview) (Box SL3)
    - 1985
      - Nov. 3, How Economic Policy Has Gone Awry.... (interview) (Box SL3)
      - Nov. 13, Nightly Business Record (Box SL3)
      - Nov.
        - Current Trends in Macroeconomic Policy in the World Economy and Deficit Financing and Its Relation to Inflation (Box SL3)
        - I mali dell'economia si combattono con il rilancio dell'Europa (interview) (Box SL3)
      - Dec. 9, Life Cycle, Individual Thrift and the Wealth of Nations - Nobel lecture, Stockholm, Sweden, Folder 1 of 2 (Box SL3)
      - Dec. 9, Life Cycle, Individual Thrift and the Wealth of Nations - Nobel lecture, Stockholm, Sweden, Folder 2 of 2 (Box SL4)
      - Dec., Institutional Investors (Box SL4)
    - 1986
      - Apr. 2 and Apr. 9 - James R. Killian, Jr., Faculty Achievement Award and Lectures, 2 folders (Box SL4)
      - Apr. 26, untitled, sesquicentennial of MIT (Box SL4)
      - Dec. 12, The Evolution of Monetary Policy (Box SL4)
    - 1987
      - Mar. 24, Public Lives of the Laureates (Box SL4)
      - Mar., untitled, University of Illinois (Box SL4)
      - May/June, The Key to Saving is Growth, Not Thrift (interview) (Box SL4)
      - Sept., Mortgage for the Young (Box SL4)
      - Oct. 30, Some Remarks on Empirical Tests of the Kaldorian Model of Saving (Box SL4)
      - The European Economic Recovery? A Need for New Policies - Lecture for J. Eliason (published 1988) (Box SL4)
    - 1988
      - Aug. 23 - Exiles documentary interview (Box SL4)
      - Sept., untitled, Aspen Institute, Italy (Box SL4)
      - Nov. 2, Is the Market Valuing Stock Rationally? (Box SL4)
      - Dec. 5, Economic Issues Facing the New President (Box SL4)
      - Conversation (interview) (Box SL4)
    - 1989
      - Jan. 25 and 1990 Jan., Il risparmio nel mezzogiorno (Box SL4)
      - Jan., Management is the Firm of the Future and CIE Plan (Box SL4)
      - June 1, L'egemonia economica americana - tramonto (Box SL4)
      - Testimony III: An Interview (Box SL5)
      - 1989-1990, Speeches and lectures (Box SL5)
      - 1989-1992 and undated, Lectures and interviews (Box SL5)
    - 1991 Feb. 8, International Monetary Fund Address (Box SL5)
    - 1991 Fall, The S and L Debate: Who Should Pay for it? (Box SL5)
    - 1992
      - Apr. 29, The Globalization of Financial Markets (Box SL5)
      - July, Emerging Problem for the American Economy (Box SL5)
    - 1993
      - June 30, Congresso Confederale CISL interview (Box SL5)
      - July 10, Modigliani, 'El gobierno no debe contener el déficit cuando la cuarta parte de la población está en el paro' (interview) (Box SL5)
      - July 11, Felipe debe encabezar una cruzada contra el paro (interview) (Box SL5)
      - Sept. 19, Los sindicatos son, en buena parte, responsables del paro en España (interview) (Box SL5)
      - Introduction to Macroeconomics, in Economics, ed. M. Parkin (Box SL5)
      - 1993-2003, Interviews - Correspondence and printed material (Box SL5)
    - 1994
      - Jan. - IAP lecture (Box SL5)
      - May 9, Introduzione economia (Box SL5)
      - May 23, L'Espresso (Box SL5)
      - Sept. 9, Corporate Finance Laboratory (Box SL5)
      - Nov. 3, Modigliani: 'Berlusconi sconfessi...' (interview) (Box SL5)
      - Dec., Five Best Economists, 2 folders (Box SL5)
    - 1995
      - Feb. 17, Primo, imparate a essere frugali: colloquio con Franco Modigliani (interview) (Box SL5)
      - Feb., Italian TV interview on Italian fiscal policy (Box SL5)
      - Mar. 15, Intervista para el Professor Modigliani (interview) (Box SL5)
      - July 10, Senza leader pronti a risanare l'Italia rischia il baratro (Box SL5)
      - July 20, Senza leader pronti a risanare l'Italia rischia il baratro (interview) (Box SL5)
      - Sept. 11, 'Moderate i salari e vi salverete' (interview) (Box SL5)
      - Nov. 2, Questa manovra o l'Italia va in tilt (interview) (Box SL5)
      - Nov. 30-Dec. 1, Unemployment and Monetary Policy, Folder 1 of 3 (Box SL5)
      - Nov. 30-Dec. 1, Unemployment and Monetary Policy, Folder 2-3 of 3 (Box SL6)
      - 1995-1996, Italian lectures - Includes paper by L. Pasinetti (Box SL6)
    - 1996
      - Mar. 25, 'Italiani, non fatevi ingannare' (interview) (Box SL6)
      - Sept. 13, Modigliani: 'Il futuro si disegna ripartendo dalle piccole aziende' (interview) (Box SL6)
    - 1997
      - June 5, Napoli, Incontro con Franco Modigliani: L'unificazione Europea e le prospettive dell'occupazione (poster) (Box SL6)
      - June 15, Defizite reduziert man nicht dem Radiergummi (interview) (Box SL6)
      - June 16, Reflessioni conclusive (Box SL6)
      - Oct. 23, Modigliani: Caro Prodi, sulle 35 ore si rischia il disastro (interview) (Box SL6)
      - Oct. 29, Relationship Between the Stock and Bond Market, 2 folders (Box SL6)
    - 1998